Guide to the Charles Humboldt Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS AND RESEARCH MATERIALS, 1935-1963; Series II; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  - Charles Humboldt - Writings (Unpublished)
    - "Note from the Front", 1945 (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - "Thirties Folksay", undated (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - "The Typical in Art", undated (Box 6, Folder 224)
    - Untitled article re: Bergman, undated (Box 6, Folder 225)
    - Untitled review of John Howard Lawson's The Hidden Heritage, undated (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Untitled review of Conor Cruise O'Brien's To Katanga and Back, undated (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Untitled review of Thomas McGrath's Witness to the Times, undated (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Untitled article re: Shakespeare, undated (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Untitled story, undated (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 6, Folder 229-230)
  - Charles Humboldt - Published Poetry
    - "The Careful Life", 1952 (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - "The Conquerors", 1954 (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - "Field of Plunder", 1952 (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - "The Fifth Season", 1959 (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - "Gen. George Fielding Eliot", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - "Hearty Charlie", 1954 (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - "In Praise of History", 1953 (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - "Jim Crow Blues", 1956 (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - "Non-Objective Art", 1954 (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - "Nothin' to Lose", 1956 (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - "The Poet Prisoner", 1955 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    - "Rite for the Anxious Mind", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    - "To Certain Men of Learning", 1954 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    - "the witness", 1952 (Box 7, Folder 235)
    - "Caresses of Life", undated (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - "Jack Sprat", undated (Box 7, Folder 236)
  - Clarence Weinstock - Writings (Published)
    - "Artists as Illustrators", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - "Communications", undated (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - "Contradictions in Abstractions", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 239)
    - "Freedom in Painting", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 240)
    - "The Frick Formula", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 241)
    - "Hard Luck Champs", 1946 (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - "Japanese Testament", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - "Jewish Immigrants", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - "Joe Jones", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - "Kropotkin's Uneasy Ghost", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 246)
    - "Letter on Salvador Dali", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 247)
    - "Liberalism", 1939 (Box 7, Folder 248)
    - "The Man in the Balloon", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 249)
    - "Nazi Mythology", 1938 (Box 7, Folder 250)
    - "Public Art in Practice", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 251)
    - "The Sculptor in Society", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 252)
    - "Studies Into Living Substance", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 253)
    - "Stunts by Strunsky", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 254)
    - "Three Penny Opera", 1938 (Box 7, Folder 255)
    - "Ultimas Obras Murales de Diego Rivera", 1953 (Box 7, Folder 256)
    - "The Union Show", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 257)
    - "Whither American Painting", 1938 (Box 7, Folder 258)
  - Clarence Weinstock - Writings (Unpublished)
    - "Effectiveness of Reserpine Tested by Conditioned Reflex Technique", undated (Box 7, Folder 259)
    - "Theory of Anxiety Presented", undated (Box 7, Folder 259)
    - "Moctezuma II, A Social Tragedy", undated (Box 7, Folder 260)
    - Notes on Mexican Muralists, undated (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - "Pre-Columbian History and Art", undated (Box 7, Folder 262)
    - "Siqueiros", undated (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - "Siqueiros" - Preface, Chapters 1-10, undated (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - "Siqueiros" - Chapters 11-18, Appendices, Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - "The University Library Mural of Juan O'Gorman", undated (Box 7, Folder 266)
    - "Why We Fight", undated (Box 7, Folder 267)
    - Untitled story re: Mexican doctor; notes and research materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 268)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 269)
  - Writings of Others
    - Anderson, Edith, translation of The Soldier of Ciotat by Bertolt Brecht, undated (Box 8, Folder 270)
    - Baxandall, Lee, "Resources for Study of Recent Slavic Literature and Slavic Criticism", undated (Box 8, Folder 271)
    - Gershgoren, Estelle, "The Trial", undated (Box 8, Folder 272)
    - Lange, Victor, "The Solitude of Jean Genet", 1963 (Box 8, Folder 273)
    - Lifschitz, Mikhail, "Giambattista Vico (1668-1744)", undated (Box 8, Folder 274)
    - Manoff, Arnold, "Chase the White Horse", undated (Box 8, Folder 275)
    - Rabinowitz, Victor, "Letter from Havana", 1960 (Box 8, Folder 276)
      See also: box 3, folder 101
    - Wortis, Avi, "The Tory", undated (Box 8, Folder 277)
  - Poetry of Others
    - Al-Bayati, Abdul W., "Poems from Exile", undated (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Alexander, Sidney, "The Riveters", 1947 (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Blake, William, "The New Jerusalem", undated (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - Brecht, Bertolt, "To Posterity", undated (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - Cardona-Hine, Alvaro:
      - "Always for All", undated (Box 8, Folder 279)
      - "Ouster in Okinawa", undated (Box 8, Folder 279)
      - "Ballad of the Landowner's Justice", undated (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - Cleghorn, Sarah N., "The Golf Links", 1876 (Box 8, Folder 280)
    - Eliot, T. S., "The Hippopotamus", 1888 (Box 8, Folder 280)
    - Eluard, Paul:
      - "The Work of the Poet", 1946 (Box 8, Folder 280)
      - "The Last Night", 1942 (Box 8, Folder 280)
      - "Full in the Month of August", 1944 (Box 8, Folder 280)
      - "A Small Number of French Intellectuals Have Placed Themselves in the Service of the Enemy", 1944 (Box 8, Folder 280)
      - "In a Black Mirror", 1944 (Box 8, Folder 280)
    - Frumkin, Gene: (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "The Debt", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "Hipster a la Mailer", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "The Builder of Clouds", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "My Eyes", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "The Face-Down Indian", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "Lenin", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "Mobile for Celena", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
      - "A Photograph", undated (Box 8, Folder 281)
    - Gershgoren, Sid: (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - "Fragment of a Journey", undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - "A Landscape by the Roadside", undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - "Dirge", undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - "Small Portrait of a Laughing Cowboy", undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - "Watermelon Fantastic", undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - "Revolution", undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
      - "The Northern Migration", undated (Box 8, Folder 282)
    - Gordon, Don, "The Fearful", undated (Box 8, Folder 283)
    - Hills, Constance G., "The Run", undated (Box 8, Folder 283)
    - Irgat, Cahit Saffet, "To a Deported Comrade", 1946 (Box 8, Folder 284)
    - Jonathan [underline], "The Dark Green on the Land", undated (Box 8, Folder 284)
    - Knight, Ralph, "My Grandfather Darby", 1946 (Box 8, Folder 284)
    - Kurnik, Stanley, "Cuba Libre", 1960 (Box 8, Folder 285)
    - Lund, Mary G.:
      - "Bohemia", undated (Box 8, Folder 285)
      - "Heidiggerian Ethics Clarified", undated (Box 8, Folder 285)
    - Mao Tse-Tung, "Swimming", 1956 (Box 8, Folder 286)
    - McGrath, Thomas: (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - "The Tourists", undated (Box 8, Folder 287)
      - "Counter-image for the World of Death", undated (Box 8, Folder 287)
    - McGraw, Edward, "Lament", undated (Box 8, Folder 287)
    - Merriam, Eve, "As a Matter of Course", undated (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Neruda, Pablo, "Ode to Thread", undated (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Rella, Ettore:
      - "The Phantom Sea", undated (Box 8, Folder 288)
      - "Ten Presentations of the Human Attitude", undated (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Replansky, Naomi, untitled, undated (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Shore, Viola Brothers, "Knightmare", undated (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Vrettakos, Niko Foros:
      - "A Letter", undated (Box 8, Folder 289)
      - "Last Supper", undated (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Whitman, Walt, "Animals", undated (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Williams, William Carlos, "The Yachts", 1883 (Box 8, Folder 290)
    - Woskoff, Verna:
      - "How Safe Can You Get?", undated (Box 8, Folder 290)
      - "Jungle Coloration", undated (Box 8, Folder 290)
    - No author: (Box 8, Folder 291)
      - "The Junk Yard", undated (Box 8, Folder 291)
      - "Ancestor Accabren", undated (Box 8, Folder 291)
      - untitled, undated (Box 8, Folder 291)
- PERSONAL AND FINANCIAL, Series III; 0.25; (1 box)
  Included in this section are a biographical sketch of Charles Humboldt, copies of his obituary from the National Guardian, medical and financial records of Clarence Weinstock, and résumés for both names.
  - Charles Humboldt and Clarence Weinstock
    - Humboldt, Charles - biographical sketch (Box 9, Folder 292)
    - Humboldt, Charles - obituaries (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - Humboldt, Charles - résumé (Box 9, Folder 294)
    - Humboldt, Charles - miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 295)
    - Weinstock, Clarence - income tax returns, 1957-1962 (Box 9, Folder 296)
    - Weinstock, Clarence - medical (Box 9, Folder 297)
    - Weinstock, Clarence - résumés (Box 9, Folder 298)